<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Child Growth Standards</string>
    <string name="birthday">Birthdate</string>
    <string name="boy">Boy</string>
    <string name="camera">Camera</string>
    <string name="cefalic_perimeter">Head circumference</string>
    <string name="cefalic_perimeter_cm">Head circumference (cm)</string>
    <string name="cefalic_perimeter_for_age">Head circumference for age</string>
    <string name="centimeter">Centimeters</string>
    <string name="chk_msg">Register measures after save</string>
    <string name="date_format">dd-mmm-yy</string>
    <string name="days">\u0020Days\u0020</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="edit">Edit child</string>
    <string name="gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="girl">Girl</string>
    <string name="height">\u0020Height\u0020</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="imc">BMI\u0020</string>
    <string name="imc_for_age">BMI for age</string>
    <string name="inches">Inches</string>
    <string name="initialize">Initializing&#8230;</string>
    <string name="kilogram">Kilograms</string>
    <string name="len_Height">Length/Height</string>
    <string name="len_Height_cm">Length/Height (cm)</string>
    <string name="len_for_age">Length/Height for age</string>
    <string name="main.emty.title">No data to show</string>
    <string name="measure_date">Measure date</string>
    <string name="months">\u0020Months\u0020</string>
    <string name="most_recent">Most recent measure</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="outOfRange">Value out of range</string>
    <string name="perimeter">Perimeter\u0020 </string>
    <string name="pounds">Pounds</string>
    <string name="rate">Rate app</string>
    <string name="record_child">Register child</string>
    <string name="record_measure">Register measures</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="seguimiento">Follow-up</string>
    <string name="select_from">Select from</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="show_perc">Show percentiles</string>
    <string name="splash_subtitle">Child Growth Standards</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Percentiles</string>
    <string name="title_activity_new_history_record">Register measures</string>
    <string name="title_activity_percentiles">Percentiles</string>
    <string name="week">\u0020week\u0020</string>
    <string name="weeks">" weeks "</string>
    <string name="weight">Weight \u0020</string>
    <string name="weightForage">Weight for age</string>
    <string name="weightForlen">Weight for Length/Height</string>
    <string name="weightHeight">Weight/Height</string>
    <string name="year">\u0020year\u0020</string>
    <string name="years">\u0020Years\u0020</string>
    <string name="perc_chart">Percentiles chart</string>
    <string name="main.empty.suggest">Register to one or more childs and start to follow-up their growth</string>
    <string name="dif_date">You can choose a different date</string>
    <string name="delete_dialog_title">Delete?</string>
    <string name="delete_dialog_content">This action will delete this child and every associated register permantly</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="aggre">Continue</string>
    <string name="duplicate_register">There is already a register for the selected date</string>

    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="start">Got it</string>

    <string name="slide_1_title">Welcome!</string>
    <string name="slide_1_desc">
        The easiest way to track your child\'s development from the first day of life to the age of 19!
        \nYou can follow one or more children at a time.
    </string>

    <string name="slide_2_title">WHO Data</string>
    <string name="slide_2_desc">
        Data used for graphs were taken from WHO\'s official web page
    </string>

    <string name="slide_3_title">Percentiles</string>
    <string name="slide_3_desc">
       The percentile curves graphs allow you to take better control over the development of your children, also allow you to detect trends in their growth!</string>

    <string name="slide_4_title">Measurements</string>
    <string name="slide_4_desc">Compare the measurements with the BMI percentile and height up to 19 years, weight up to 10 years, cephalometric perimeter and weight for height up to 5 years.</string>


    <string-array name="weight_units">
        <item>Kilograms</item>
        <item>Pounds</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="height_units">
        <item>Centimeters</item>
        <item>Inches</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="pref_height_unit_title">Length Unit</string>
    <string name="pref_weight_unit_title">Weight unit</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="age">Age:\u0020</string>
    <string name="pref_summary">Select measure unit to show</string>

    <string name="hellp">
        Growth is not only a result of nutrition but inherited factors.
         Ethnicity can influence growth patterns of a child, so some
         countries have their own curves Growth Standards. However, the curves
         Growth patterns of the World Health Organization (WHO) are used
         more frequently and are considered the standard worldwide. \n\n

        <b>
            How to take measure? \n\n
            Head circunference \n\n
        </b>

      The measurement should be taken with a tape that does not stretch.
         Typically it has done with a flexible metal tape measure. To measure, wrap the tape
         tightly around the point where the head circumference is greater. Usually this happens
         on the forehead, one to two fingers above the eyebrows, and behind, the most prominent area
         the back of the head. \n

       During the early years of a child\'s life, head circumference is an important measure
         because indirectly it reflects the size and growth of the brain.
    </string>
    <string name="help2">
\n\n

        <b>Length / Height</b>
\n\n
The length is the linear measurement of infants up to 24 months. The measures of length (instead of height) can also be taken for children between 24 and 36 months of age who are unable to stand unassisted.
The length is measured with the lying child. The most accurate way of measuring length is to use a table gage length. Tables length measurement must have a fixed head and a movable foot perpendicular to the surface of the table part.
To measure the child\'s place in the table with the head touching the fixed part. Make sure you do not have shoes or anything in the hair. An assistant can help you hold the child to keep him still and focused on the table. Straighten your legs and adjust the moving part so that the soles of the feet are still against it.
        The length is an important determinant of the nutritional status of a child. It is possible that the length of a child grow very slowly if you have been starved for long.
\n\n\n
      <b>  Weight</b>
\n\n
Weight is a measure taken throughout life to help determine trends and current nutritional status.
The weight of an infant can be measured accurately using multiple computers. A pediatric balance plate allows weighing the lying child. These pediatric electronic scales can be fixed or sliding weights, and are accurate to 10 grams. Another option is a hanging scale, which is attached to a firm structure (eg a beam or a door frame) and child hangs in the balance with weighing pants.
To take the measurement, make sure the child takes the least amount of clothes and that nobody is touching.\n\n

        If not available a pediatric scale, a scale can be used for adults. Despite an adult first and then weigh the same adult with the child in her arms. Calculate the difference between the two weights to find the weight of the infant.
        \n\n

        The weight-for-age is an important indicator of the nutritional status of a child and may indicate long-term trends such as a weight below expectations.\n\n

        The weight-length relationship, on the other hand, helps determine the current nutritional status. This is the key indicator to determine malnutrition in children.

\n\n\n
      <b>Body mass index (BMI)</b>
\n\n
      The body mass index is a
number that is calculated based on the weight and height of
A boy or a girl. The BMI is used as a tool to identify possible weight problems for children who may
Lead to health problems.

    </string>





    <string name="percentil_desc">
   In WHO Growth Standards curves five curves are shown
        (Red, orange and green) corresponding to the percentiles
         P3, P15, P50, P85 and P97 in order from the bottom up.\n\n
       The central curve or 50th percentile is the mean or average.
         A child with normal growth typically have a growth curve approximately parallel to the average.
         A single point is not enough to accurately assess a child\'s growth.
     a number of points are needed to understand the patterns and trends of a child\'s growth over time.
    </string>

    <string name="weight_desc">
            Children could be considered underweight if their weight for age is below the 15th percentile.
         One point that falls below the 3rd percentile weight could indicate severely underweight, indicating that the child needs special care.
         The severely underweight can result from delayed growth, malnutrition or both.
        \n\n
        In any case if the measures fall into one of the percentiles limits is lower or higher is recommended consult your doctor about health
         your child.
    </string>

    <string name="height_desc">
        The growth of a child is considered delayed if its length for age remains
         below the percentile 15th. Infants and toddlers with delayed growth may recover part
         growth potential if their nutrition is improved before 2 years of age.
         However, for children older than 2 years who are in situations of nutritional deprivation,
         the delay in growth could be virtually irreversible.
        \n\n
      In any case if the measures fall into one of the percentiles limits is lower or higher is recommended consult your doctor about health
         your child.
    </string>

    <string name="weight_for_height_desc">
           Children could be seen in malnutrition if your weight for height/length is below the 15th percentile.
        Malnutrition is a major cause of mortality for children under 5 years
         so a child who is assessed as [[malnourished]] requires immediate medical attention.
         Children who have weight for length above the 85th percentile are considered overweight and may be at risk for childhood obesity.
        \n\n
        In any case if the measures fall into one of the percentiles limits is lower or higher is recommended consult your doctor about health
         your child.

    </string>

<string name="cefalic_desc">
        Children whose head circumference is below the 15th percentile could be considered microcephalic.
         By contrast, the macrocephaly is a condition that indicates when the head circumference is above the 85th percentile.
         It is important that a physician assess children that are micro or macrocephalic. It could have serious medical implications,
         since it is assumed that the head circumference serves as a basic indicator of brain growth.
    \n\n
       In any case if the measures fall into one of the percentiles limits is lower or higher is recommended consult your doctor about health
         your child.
    </string>

    <string name="imc_desc">
      The Body Mass Index (BMI) is a measure that associates weight and height to determine the nutritional status of an individual.\n\n

        If your child\'s BMI is below the 15th percentile, it is considered to be underweight. \n
        If your child\'s BMI is between the 15-85 percentiles, it is considered a healthy weight. \n
        If your child\'s BMI is between the 85-97 percentiles, it is considered to be overweight. \n
       If it is above the 97th percentile it is considered obese.  \n \n

        In any case if the measures fall into one of the percentiles limits is lower or higher is recommended consult your doctor about health
         your child..
    </string>
    <string name="share_using">Share using:</string>
    <string name="share_app_msg">\nFollow your child\'s growth up easily with this app.\n\n</string>

    <string name="show_marker">Show marker</string>
    <string name="show_marker_desc">
        Enable a marker that show the selected point values on the graphs.
    </string>
    <string name="graph_empty">No data to show</string>
    <string name="later">Later</string>
    <string name="no_thank">No thanks</string>
    <string name="rate2">Rate</string>
    <string name="rate_dlg_desc">Thanks for using this application, if you liked or think it is useful, please comment that it seems to you or if you have any suggestions.</string>
    <string name="rate_dlg_title">What do you think?</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="activity.chil.name.error">Enter a minimum of 2 characters</string>
    <string name="in_av">In</string>
    <string name="measure">Measure</string>
    <string name="p15">Percentile 15</string>
    <string name="p3">Percentile 3</string>
    <string name="p50">Percentile 50</string>
    <string name="p85">Percentile 85</string>
    <string name="p97">Percentile 97</string>
    <string name="week_av">w</string>
    <string name="year_av">y</string>
    <string name="day">\u0020day\u0020</string>
    <string name="month">\u0020month\u0020</string>
    <string name="show_measure_list">Show measures</string>
    <string-array name="measure_options">
        <item>Edit</item>
        <item>Delete</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="measures">Measures</string>
    <string name="date">Date</string>
    <string name="delete_measure_dialog_content">Remove entry of measurements for this date?</string>
    <string name="sec_childs_title">Register child</string>
    <string name="sec_childs_title2">Navigation</string>
    <string name="sec_new_childs_content">Select a photo from the gallery or take one from the camera</string>
    <string name="sec_new_childs_title">Sets an image</string>
    <string name="sec_new_history_content">Data are suggested based on the age of the infant</string>
    <string name="sec_new_childs_title2">Select the date of birth</string>
    <string name="sec_new_history_title">Enter the measure</string>
    <string name="sec_new_history_title2">"Select the measurement unit "</string>
    <string name="sec_new_history_title3">Select the measurement date</string>
    <string name="sec_new_history_title4">Save data</string>
    <string name="sec_quick_percentil_title">Select the type of chart</string>
    <string name="sec_quick_percentil_title2">Check measurements on different charts</string>
    <string name="info">Information</string>
</resources>